# **Matt Roth**

# **Fullstack Web Developer**

mattroth.dev@gmail.com | 1 (818) 331-0729 | www.mattroth.dev

## **OBJECTIVE**

- Enthusiastic developer seeking to fill a Junior Web Developer position that will allow my skills to grow alongside the success of the company. Optimistic, motivated to continuously improve my skills, and well-suited to working on a team.
- 1.5 years of professional experience in working with modern web development technologies, including Django, React/Typescript, Git, and Azure DevOps. Has experience working remotely.

#### **SUMMARY**

Intrinsically motivated developer specializing in JavaScript and JavaScript based frameworks. Competent in Git version control systems, Python, and has some experience in designing database schema. Primarily works in Linux operating system environments, but is comfortable in Windows and Mac environments as well. Possesses a B.A. in Biological Anthropology, 1.5 years of professional experience, and a genuine enjoyment of learning.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS/SASS, Python
- Frameworks: Bootstrap, Tachyons, Styled Components, React, Django, Gatsby
- Databases: Sqlite3, GraphQL
- OS: Linux, Windows, OSX
- Version Control: Git, GitHub, Azure DevOps
- Tools: Visual Studio Code, Chrome Dev Tools, Firefox Dev Tools, Postman, Netlify

#### **EDUCATION**

**University of California Santa Barbara**, Goleta, CA — B.A Biological Anthropology

AUGUST 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2018

**Pasadena City College**, Pasadena, CA — A.A. Anthropology, A.A. Italian

AUGUST 2012 - SEPTEMBER 2016

#### **WORK HISTORY**

# **Acclaim Academic Institute,** La Palma, CA / Remote — Fullstack Web Developer

OCTOBER 2019 - JANUARY 2021

Fulfilled the role of full stack developer in producing new features and improving performance for an online learning and scheduling platform. Gained experience in React/Typescript front end development, as well as Django back end development and database management. Projects included: an interactive avatar builder for student accounts, a vocabulary database and search tool, and improvements to a shared interactive, real-time IDE used for teaching Python.

## Ilinx Studios, Hollywood, CA — Fullstack Web Developer

IUNE 2019 - OCTOBER 2019

Worked on a 5 person dev team. Gained experience working with Python, the Flask framework, and gained knowledge regarding game design and product development cycles. Configured a JavaScript webapp to utilize real-time stock information, and implemented a user sign-up/sign-in framework to prepare the company's gaming platform, Whale, for its beta launch.